<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Menaces With Splinters on Legendary Sleeper</title>
    <link>https://stayinside4ever.github.io/tags/menaces-with-splinters/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Menaces With Splinters on Legendary Sleeper</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://stayinside4ever.github.io/tags/menaces-with-splinters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluehammers - Year 2</title>
      <link>https://stayinside4ever.github.io/post/bluehammers-year-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 20:57:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stayinside4ever.github.io/post/bluehammers-year-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a fortress diary for my splinter for the splinter project &amp;ldquo;Menaces With Splinters&amp;rdquo; for the game Dwarf Fortress. Read more about the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/menaceswithsplinters&#34;&gt;its subreddit&lt;/a&gt;.
Also, I called my fort Bluehammers because I want to have a squad of hammerdwarves with blue cloaks. No reason for that, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally have an underground well next to our dormitory/hospital area. No more running to the nearby brook! Soon after that, an elven caravan arrives. Normally, we would slaughter every single one of them and claim all of the useless wooden junk they brought along, but that might be hard to do with the one axeman we have, so we proceed to trade them some mugs for a coyote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We notice a dwarf from our starting seven has died somehow. It is &amp;ldquo;Grower&amp;rdquo; Enasamost, Woodcutter. No one has any idea how he died. Oh well, rest in peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felsite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parts of the caverns start collapsing for no reason. This lasts a couple of days until a forgotten beast appears in them. It&amp;rsquo;s Donu Simoaril - a squirming, fidgeting, huge three-eyed rhinoceros with large mandibles and long, straight mauve hair. We were preparing to beware of its fire, but as suddenly as it appeared, it wandered away in the caverns and never showed up again. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hematite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start flooring the way for trade caravans to go through a little labyrinth before arriving to the depot and also barracks at the entrance. A squad of six hammerdwarves is assembled and called &amp;ldquo;The Oily Razors&amp;rdquo;. A bit ironic for a smashing weapon squad. The axeman from the starting seven also gets drafted in the squad. They&amp;rsquo;re all given freshly smithed silver war hammers and put to sparring. A weapon trap full of spiked wood balls is also set up at the &amp;ldquo;shortcut&amp;rdquo; entrance to the middle of the fortress, in case any enemies manage to slip by our military unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malachite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally set up four underground farms and immediately assign a couple more dwarves to farming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few corridors for levers are ordered to be dug out next to the dining hall, and further down the hall a little notch in the wall with a chair in it is made for our manager/bookkeeper, so he can sit there all day and write records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galena&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dwarf just got a strange mood! What could he make? A legendary weapon? Armor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s a lignite crown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hardworker (a hauling/odd job labor I made) Mosus Ducimdolil has created Salularak, a lignite crown. It is encircled with bands of rectangular lignite cabochons, oval kaolininte cabochons, yak bone and silver. On the item is an image of Rifafa Wonderqueen the elf and dwarves in kaolinite. The dwarves are prostrating themselves before Rifafa Wonderqueen. The artwork relates to the defeat of The Tool of Glorifying by The Youthful Jaws and lordship of the elf Rifafa Wonderqueen over at Searedmachine in the early spring of 78 during The Conquest of Searedmachine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get it, Mosus, we should have killed the elves from that caravan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the disappointing artifact&amp;rsquo;s (read: soon-to-be trade good) creation we proceed to dig a moat around the walls of our fortress, which is proving a little difficult, because we were dumb enough to make the inside of the walls cross the brook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limestone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, crossing the brook isn&amp;rsquo;t the only stupid thing we did. We were wondering, why the floor of the moat was getting covered in cave moss. Looking around the area, we noticed that it intersects our coop, which was directly below surface. We built a new wall for the coop and proceeded digging. However, a goose managed to somehow get stuck on one piece of dirt on the wall side of the moat and won&amp;rsquo;t come down. Guess it&amp;rsquo;s staying there forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also start work on dyeing some of our pig tail cloth blue for the purposes of making blue cloaks for our hammerdwarf squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally got enough male migrants to complete our hammerdwarf squad. Just in time for the blue cloaks, too! Now our fort can truly be called Bluehammers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another dwarf got into a mood! Please be something useful&amp;hellip; please?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stodir Ebaloddom, Stonecrafter has created Nonshutugzol Ngalakothduk, a tetrahedrite crown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; my god.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is encircled with bands of round tetrahedrite cabochons. On the item is an image of Penopu Mountainivy the elf and dwarves in wood opal. The dwarves are prostrating themselves before Penopu Mountainivy. The artwork related to the defeat of The Tool of Glorifying by The Youthful Jaws and lordship of the elf Penopu Mountainivy over at Frenzyswords in the early summer of 78 during The Conquest of Frenzyswords. On the item is an image of a octagon cut gem in mango wood. On the item is an image of two square cut gems in lychee wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fine, fine, we&amp;rsquo;ll kill everyone in the next elven caravan, just. Please, stop making images of dwarves prostrating in front of elves. It&amp;rsquo;s humiliating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another dwarf has died&amp;hellip;. from dehydration. Our booze stockpiles are full - how could it have happened? It&amp;rsquo;s another woodcutter - Tobul Stibmeroslan. We make a coffin for him, too, and a few more in advance, in case we need them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moonstone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A snatcher has been noticed just outside our fort! It&amp;rsquo;s quite close to the entrance, so we make our hammerdwarf squad go after him. We&amp;rsquo;re catching up, about to smash his head in&amp;hellip; and our hammerdwarves run away in horror. In the name of Armok, get your plump helmets together! That&amp;rsquo;s it, we&amp;rsquo;re making a statue garden deep underground with a puppy pit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The puppy fall is complete, and we test it with a couple of puppies and an alpaca. Our military didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to feel anything while watching the animals explode from a 30-level fall and gained a little discipline, which will hopefully help in the future. We add a few statues at the bottom to make a statue garden for the other dwarves, so they could gain a little discipline, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a couple dwarves are engraving, we notice a lot of miasma appearing in the garden. At first, we can&amp;rsquo;t find the source, but then we look at the stairs we made next to the puppy-pitting channel and notice a few rotten body parts there. It&amp;rsquo;s a pain, but we channel down the staircase, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obsidian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We add 10 silver statues to the freshly engraved bottom of the puppy fall. Dwarves immediately start gathering there. We throw down a couple more animals and no one seems to react in any way. We just assume their discipline grew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also make a slaughter-room for pet alpacas, bunnies and such. Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s fun, second, you can&amp;rsquo;t butcher someone&amp;rsquo;s pet, so they&amp;rsquo;re a bit useless, since we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to only focus on birds and sheep. It was quite successful in impaling a few pets with spears, but a horse and cow kid were quite persistent and dodged the spears until they starved to death. We dumped all the remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our miners finally finished digging the 256 bedroom area. Time to get some furniture in there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total dwarves at the end of the year: 52&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; starting dwarves still alive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artifacts: 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>